A Guide to the Tuckahoe Garden Club records, 1928-2006
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Tuckahoe Garden Club records, 1928-2006
The Library of Virginia
42687, 43740
8.3 cu. ft. (24 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Tuckahoe Garden Club, 2006 (Accession 42687).
Gift of the Tuckahoe Garden Club, 2008 (Accession 43740).
Biographical Information
The Tuckahoe Garden Club of Westhampton was formed 16 May 1928 and became a member of The Garden Club of Virginia in 1933 and of The Garden Club of America in 1952. The Club is organized exclusively for charitable and educational purposes, including the education of its members and the general public by advancing interest in and promoting gardening among amateurs; by lobbying for protection of our native resources; by restoring, preserving and documenting historic gardens; and by encouraging civic planting and roadside beautification. Throughout it's history the Club has been involved in a variety of programs, from restoration of the gardens at the John Marshall House, publication of the Gardening Guide, donations to the Science Museum and Richmond Public Library for planting projects, and the sponsorship of talks and symposiums.
Scope and Content
Records, 1928-2006, of the Tuckahoe Garden Club of Westhampton, including annual reports, budgets, clippings, correspondence, minutes, publications, and yearbooks. Also included are associated files of the Garden Club of America and the Garden Club of Virginia.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Minutes, 1928-2006
Series II. Administrative records, 1928-2002
Series III. Projects, 1965-2002
Series IV. Subject files, 1932-2000
Series V. Garden Club of Virginia- Garden Club of America, 1956-2004
Contents List
- Series I. Minutes, 1928-2006., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 1-7)
  This series includes minutes for monthly, executive, and membership meetings. The minutes include agendas, attendance, clippings, correspondence, financial reports, newsletters, program ideas, reports, and other materials detailing the activities of the club.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Minutes, 1928-1930. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1930-1933. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1933-1935. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1935-1939. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1940-1948. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1949-1950. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1951-1953. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1954-1955. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1956-1957. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1958-1960. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1961-1962. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1963-1964. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1965-1966. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1967-1968. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1969-1970. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1971-1972. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1973-1974. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1973-1979. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1975. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1977. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1980-1981. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1983. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1984. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1985. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1986. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1987. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1988. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1989. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1992. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1993. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1994. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1995. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1996. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1997. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1998. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1999. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2000. (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Minutes, 2001. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Minutes, 2001-2002. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2002 January-June. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2002 July-December. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2003 January-April. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2003 May-October. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2003 November-December. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2004. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2005. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2006. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series II: Administrative records, 1928-2002 (bulk 1975-2000)., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 8-12)
  This series includes budgets, clippings, correspondence, histories, publications, reports, and yearbooks. Included are annual reports by the treasurers, board and other chairwomen; copies of the Gardening Guide, a compiled monthly list of gardening tips; and yearbooks, 1930-2002, containing lists of officers, histories, programs, and member information. The histories include clippings, correspondence, written histories, reports, and photographs. Also included are committee notes; memorials to members; photographs; and revisions to the constitutions and by-laws.
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Annual reports, 1929-1946. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Annual reports, 1947-1949. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Annual reports, 1950-1952. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Annual reports, 1976-1979. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Annual reports, 1994-2000. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Annual reports, 2000-2002. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Annual reports, nd. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Budgets, 1982-1993. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Budgets, 1994-1998. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Budgets, 1999-2002. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Chairwomen assignments and duties, 1978-2000. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1968-1979. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1980-2000. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Conservation Committee, 1999. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1956-1999. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1999. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2001. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising, 2000. (Box 10, Folder 3-6)
  - Gardening Guide, c. 1970s. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Gardening Guide, c. 1980s. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Gardening Guide, 1990-1998. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Gardening Guide [copyright, order forms], 1983. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Gardening Guide [reports], 1984-1992. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Gifts Committee, 2000-2002. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - History of the Tuckahoe Garden Club, 1928-1968. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - History of the Tuckahoe Garden Club, 1968-1995. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - History of the Tuckahoe Garden Club, 1996-2000. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Membership Committee, 1999-2001. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Memorials, 1970-1993. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1998-2000. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Officers, 2000-2001. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, c. 1980-2000. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Receipts, 1995. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Speech, nd. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Tax exempt status, 1985-1995. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Visiting Garden Committee, 1995-1998. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Yearbooks, 1930-1935. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Yearbooks, 1935-1940. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Yearbooks, 1977-1978. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Yearbooks, 2000-2001. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Yearbooks, 2001-2002. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Yearbooks [designs], c. 1986. (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Series III: Projects, 1965-2002., Extent: 2.5 boxes. (Box 13-15)
  This series includes clippings, correspondence, photographs, programs, and reports documenting projects sponsored by the Tuckahoe Garden Club. Major projects include the restoration of the gardens at the Edgar Allen Poe Museum, John Marshall House, and the Micro-Climate Wall at the Science Museum of Virginia. Also included is information on Massie Medal Awards received; grants to Lewis Ginter Botanical Garden, Richmond Hill garden, and renovations at Richmond Library Park. Educational programs include composting projects, flower arranging courses, and lectures with Sheila McQueen and Martha Stewart.
  - Bandy Field, 2000-2002. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Better Housing Coalition, 1999-2000. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Christmas workshops, 1984-2001. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cocktail party, 1979-1999. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Compost project, 1993-1995. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Edgar Allen Poe Museum, 1996. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Flower arranging courses, 1968-1979. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Flowers shows, 1968-1994. (Box 13, Folder 8-8a)
  - Garden Week, 1970-1980. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Garden Week, 1996-1999. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Garden Week, 2000-2002. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - General ideas, 1980-1989. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - General ideas, 1990-1999. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - General ideas, 2000-2001. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Geranium sale, 2001-2002. (Box 14, Folder 1a)
  - Greening in the city, 2000. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Kent-Valentine House, 2001-2002. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - John Marshall House, 1965-1982. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Massie medal, 1968-1992. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Maymont Flower and Garden Show, 1990-2001. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Nature Camp, 2000. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Hill, 1993-1998. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Library Park, 1997-2000. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Riparian Buffer, c. 2000. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Saunders slide collection, 2001. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Science Museum microclimate wall, 2000. (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
  - S.E.E.D.S., 2001. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sheila MacQueen, 1970-1989. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Sheila MacQueen, 1990-1998. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Martha Stewart, 1989. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Thomas Hospice Rooftop Garden, 2000. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Museum Fine Arts and Flowers, 2000. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Woodham fund raiser, 2000. (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Subject files, 1932-2000., Extent: 1.5 boxes. (Box 15-16)
  This series includes miscellaneous subject files and a scrapbook of the Tuckahoe Garden Club. Included are clippings regarding conservation, flower arranging, and native plants, as well as copies of the newsletter, Garden Gossip. The scrapbook includes newspaper clippings regarding the club.
  - Chesapeake Bay Foundation, 1988-1999. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Conservation, 1993-1997. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Floral arrangement, nd. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Native plants, 1997. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, Garden Gossip, 1932-1951. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous, 1999-2000. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Viburnum Plant Study, 1993. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Publication, American Heritage, August/September 1978. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1976. (Box 16, Folder volume)
- Series V: GCV-GCA, 1956-2004., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 17-24)
  This series includes annual reports, correspondence, directories, handbooks, manuals, meeting minutes, newsletters, programs, and reports relating to the Garden Club of Virginia and the Garden Club of America.
  Arranged into two subseries.
  - Subseries 1: Garden Club of Virginia, 1960-2001.
    Includes annual meeting and board of governor meeting minutes, correspondence, directories, flower shows notes and programs, newsletters, and reports relating to the Garden Club of Virginia.
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1973. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1974. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1975. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1976. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1977. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1978. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1979. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1981. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1984. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1984. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 2000. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Annual meeting minutes, 2001. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1973. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1974. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1975. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1977. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1978. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1979. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1980. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 1982. (Box 17, Folder volume)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 2000. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Board of Governors' meeting minutes, 2001. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Calendar, 1999-2001. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Conservation Forum, 2000. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1995-2002. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Directories, 2000-2002. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Flower shows, Amateur, 1961. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Flower shows, Daffodil, 1965-1969. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Flower shows, Daffodil, 1971-1979. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Flower shows, Daffodil, 1997. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Flower shows, Daffodil, 2000-2001. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Flower shows, Lily, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Flower shows, Lily, 1971-1974. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Flower shows, Lily, 1980. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Flower shows, Lily, 1996. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Flower shows, Lily, 2000-2001. (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Flower shows, Rose, 1963-1968. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Flower shows, Rose, 1970-1979. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Flower shows, Rose, 1980-1986. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Flower shows, Rose, 2000-2001. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Flower shows, Miscellaneous notes, 1990-1999. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Handbooks, 1985, 2001. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Horticulture Committee, 1998-2001. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Legislative Day, 2001-2002. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 2001. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Newsletters, Journal, Miscellaneous, 1978. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Newsletters, Journal, 1999-2000. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Newsletters, Journal, 2001-2004. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Newsletters, Update, 1999-2001. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Newsletters, miscellaneous, 2001. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - President's book, 1973-1975. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - President's reports, 1974-1975. (Box 19, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 1975-1976. (Box 19, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 1977. (Box 19, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 1978. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 1979. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - President's reports (2 copies), 1982. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 1982-1983. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 1984. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 1985. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - President's reports, 2000-2001. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Register, 1999-2001. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Register, 2001-2002. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Speaker series lectures, 2000-2002. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: Garden Club of America, 1956-2004.
    Includes annual reports, correspondence, directories, handbooks, manuals, minutes, and newsletters relating to the Garden Club of America.
    - Annual reports, 1979-1980. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting, 1980. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - Annual reports, 1980-1981. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - Annual reports (2 copies), 1981-1982. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting, 1982. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting, List of delegates, 1982. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting, 1983. (Box 20, Folder volume)
    - Annual meeting, 1998. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Annual meeting, 1999. (Box 20, Folder 5a)
    - Annual meeting, 2000. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Annual meeting, 2001. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1977. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2002. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Directory, 2000-2001. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Flower shows, 1965-1982. (Box 21, Folder 4a)
    - Founders Fund, 2000-2002. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - The Garden Locator, 1956. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Hand Book, 1977. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Hand Book Supplement, 1977. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Hand Book of the U.S. Congress, 2001-2002. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Horticulture Committee, 1987-2002. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - H.J.R. 478, 1993. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Francis K. Hutchinson National Medal, 1998-2001. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Information Manual, 2001. (Box 22, Folder 6-8)
    - Insurance, 2001. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Cynthia Pratt Laughlin Medal, 2002. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters, Bulletin, 1994-2000. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Newsletters, Bulletin, 2001-2004. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Newsletters, Conservation Watch, 2001. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Newsletters, Flower Arranging, 1999-2000. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Newsletters, Garden Club of America By Design, 2000-2001. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Nominating Committee, 2000. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Overview of the Garden Club of America, 2000. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Plant exchange, 2001. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - President's book, 1973-1975. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Scenic Virginia, 1998-1999. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Zone VII, Directories, 1999-2000. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Zone VII, Directories, 2000-2002. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Zone VII, Meeting, 1972. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Zone VII, Meeting, 1973-1975. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Zone VII, Meeting, 1976. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Zone VII, Meeting, 1990. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Zone VII, Meeting, 2000. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Zone VII, Meeting, 2001. (Box 24, Folder 6)